GOURI BAJPAI

747-256-2121 | gouri.bajp@gmail.com | Fremont, CA | LinkedIn | Behance | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Bilingual UX Researcher and Entrepreneur with a background in information technology, commerce, and fine art, and a passion for developing intuitive, useful, human-centered designs. I strive to tackle design problems by using empathy and employing UX research methods. Founder and CEO of two successful small businesses. Familiarity with HTML, CSS, and Java helps me to communicate with the development team.

SKILLS

Tools: Figma, Miro, Maze, Usability Hub, Zoom, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Google Suite, Canva, Notion, Jira, Slack

Strengths: Double Diamond Design Process, User-Centered Design, UX Design, Research planning and design, Survey design, Remote and in-person research, Moderating research sessions, User Research - Qualitative, Quantitative, Card sorting, Collecting & Integrating User Feedback, Competitive Analysis (SWOT), Sketching, UI Design, Storyboarding, Personas, User Stories, User Flows, Sitemap, Wireframes, Low & High Fidelity Prototyping, Usability Testing, Mock-ups

EDUCATION

Master Of Science (IT) Dr. C.V. Raman University	2021
Certificate, UX/UI Design Thinkful	2021
Master Of Arts Dr. Harisingh Gour University	1999
Bachelor of Commerce Dr. Harisingh Gour University	1997

UX RESEARCH & DESIGN PROJECTS

VS | Role: UX Researcher, UX Designer, UI Designer | Project Link

- Designed a mobile app allowing high schoolers to view nearby volunteer experiences
- Users can directly communicate with people who seek help in an open room setup
- Designed a high-fidelity prototype in III weeks to reach MVP standards using Figma,
 Miro, zoom, and Maze

Flight Ez | Role: UX Researcher, UX Designer | Project Link

- Designed a mobile app that allows private pilots and student pilots to filter the aircraft based on their specs. and book an aircraft conveniently
- Tools used Figma, Adobe XD, Miro, Maze, Canva

Bus King | Role: UX Researcher, UX Designer I Project Link

- Designed a mobile app to help bus riders view bus schedules and identify travel time
- It allows commuters to identify which bus arrivals in a Mid-Sized Metropolitan City
- Tools used Pen and paper, Figma, Miro, Maze, Usability hub

EXPERIENCE

Founder/UX Researcher | SF Henna Arts | Fremont, CA

May 2012 – Present

- Collected qualitative data to understand user motivations, thoughts, and attitudes to uncover the 'why' and develop a deep understanding of the problem
- Facilitated moderated and unmoderated usability testing
- Secured partnerships and hosted booths at corporate events for over 20 companies including KPMG, CA Technologies, VISA, Verisign, and Amazon
- Collaborated with clients to understand their needs, interests, budget, and timeline to provide custom henna artwork for special occasions - earning a 5-star review on Google Business

UX Researcher & Designer | Radiant Art Studios | Fremont, CA

May 2015 - Oct 2020

- Conducted UX research including user interviews, targeted ethnography, survey development, and usability testing
- Performed quantitative and qualitative research followed by competitive analysis to understand user's pain points and user stories and market needs
- Managed marketing, social media, and inventory and successfully grew the business by 63% in 12 months

UX Designer | Fidypay | Indore, MP (Remote)

May 2017 - Jan 2020

- Participated in research using Heuristic Evaluation, facilitated qualitative research interviews
- Translated concepts into personas, journey maps, empathy maps, user flows, and user stories led to intuitive user experiences, contributed as a visual designer
- Facilitated moderated and unmoderated usability testing

Web Designer Faculty Member | Fremont USD

Sep 2012 - May 2014

• Taught HTML and CSS to students under Web Design Program

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Boldly Me (Non-Profit Organization)

Aug 2012 – Present

- Donate hours for temporary henna tattoo art and generate funds throughout the year
 Sankara Eye Care Foundation
 Sep 2012 Present
 - Participate in their fundraising events by donating canvas oil paintings

Thornton Junior High School

Sep 2017 – Present

• Event Manager and Parent Teacher Student Association Historian

Boys Scout of America Troop 449

Sep 2019 – Present

Committee member